Shahrukh Ahmed Siddiqui

About

An Android developer with 3+ years of experience in apps and SDK development in Agile teams. Currently, I'm working as a Software Engineer at M800, building a communication platform for our wide range of users.

Skills

Extensive knowledge and experience in Android app and SDK development with documentation

Experience in project management - Jira, VCS - Git, CICD - Jenkins all in Scrum environment

Development practices like Clean architecture - MVP, Dependency Injection - Dagger 2, Reactive Programming - RxJava 2

Hands on experience with SQLite, GreenDao, Realm, Room, OkHttp, Volley, Retrofit, EventBus, Firebase and more

Some experience in back-end RESTful API development using Django with Python and self-hosting on AWS servers

Professional Experience

M800 Limited, Software Engineer
09/2018 – present | Kowloon, Hong Kong
Working with SDK development team, focused on
building communication solutions for our clients and one
in-house app having 1M+ downloads.

- Refactoring and bug fixing in three of our SDK.
- Plan and design of 2 new SDK with different teams.
- Documentation for different components in SDK.

Teamie Services, *Software Developer* 07/2016 – 09/2018 | New Delhi, India Extensively worked with Android, back-end, UI/UX development teams and senior executives to implement new features while fixing bugs on the way.

- Lead the development of a new app from scratch.
- Refactoring a big part of the code base.
- Re-writing the entire database schema.
- Revamping the UI of almost the entire app.
- Implementation of many new workflows and adding new features.

Personal Projects

iTunes Search.

https://github.com/shahrukhamd/iTunes-Search
Sample Android project demonstrating the
implementation of iTunes search API and usage of
ExoPlayer to stream audio from response.

Hello Kotlin, https://github.com/shahrukhamd/HelloKotlin An open source Android project built with Kotlin programming language. It fetches, parses and shows the list of photos from a sample data API. It also shows the usage of RxJava and Retrofit with Kotlin.

Blaze File Manager,

https://github.com/shahrukhamd/BlazeFileManager
An open source project to demonstrate the Clean
Architecture by Uncle Bob. It uses MVP (Model-View-Presenter) design pattern which decouples code into different easy-to-manage layers thereby improving code flexibility and greatly reducing maintenance time.

Pseudo Data.

https://github.com/shahrukhamd/PseudoData
An open source project using the pseudo data to
demonstrate MVP design pattern dependency injection
using the Dagger2 library and its implementation in
Android, reactive programming using RxJava. It uses
Retrofit2 for APIs integration.

Text Faces,

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.sasiddiqui.textfaces It is a free keyboard app for Android devices which has 200+ text emoticons like へ(ツ)_/¯

Earthquake App,

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.shahrukhamd.earthquakeapp The very first Android app built and published by me. It can track worldwide earthquakes from USGS and plot them on Google maps.

Education

Uttar Pradesh Technical University,

Bachelor of Technology

08/2012 - 06/2016 | G. Noida, India

An engineering degree with **major in computer science**, completed with **2 internships** in Android app development.